Associated Actors and Artists Papers 5267
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Associated Actors and Artists Papers
1940-1952
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Associated Actors and Artistes of America
5267
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Interviews, questionnaires, statistics.
Consist primarily of reports and supporting research materials collected for a study on the proposed merger of several performers' unions affiliated with the Associated Actors and Artistes of America. The unions were: Actors' Equity Association (AEA); American Federation of Radio Artists (AFRA); American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA); Television Authority (TVA); American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA); and Chorus Equity Association (CEA).
2294679
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 01, 2007
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Study conducted by a committee of three professors of industrial and labor relations in order to advise six Associated Actors and Artistes of America (AAAA) unions on their proposed merger.
The merger study (1951-1952) by Robert Aronson (New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations), and Edgar Warren and Michael Komaroff (Institute of Industrial and Labor Relations, University of California at Los Angeles) examined the structure, administration, finances and problems of jurisdiction of the various performers' unions, and made proposals for the design and functions of the combined organization.
Scope and Contents
Consist primarily of reports and supporting research materials collected for a study on the proposed merger of several performers' unions affiliated with the Associated Actors and Artistes of America. The unions were: Actors' Equity Association (AEA); American Federation of Radio Artists (AFRA); American Guild of Variety Artists (AGVA); Television Authority (TVA); American Guild of Musical Artists (AGMA); and Chorus Equity Association (CEA).
Materials include a study proposal; questionnaires; interview transcripts; lists of members; notes on socio- economic data on employees and unions; charts on union structure; reports of the study committee; notes and reports of conferences between the research committee and officers of the New York City, Chicago, and Los Angeles local unions regarding merger proposals (1952); correspondence, chiefly of Professor Robert Aronson and Professor Edgar Warren with Louis Simon (AEA), and Frank Reel and Raymond Jones (AFRA), on the merger proposals (1951-1952); and memoranda on the AFRA National Board meeting; (TVA) merger proposals; the constitution for a proposed merger of TVA and AFRA; and reports by Bernard and Reis Company, Margaret Webster and Edward Bernays pertaining to AAAA mergers (1940- 1949).
Research materials used by Aronson, Warren and Komaroff to study the organizational functions and structure of AAAA include research notes on union jurisdiction, collective agreements, dues, and economic problems of the member unions; union documents such as constitutions, work rules and collective agreements; financial statements; codes of fair practice; permits and rules governing performers' agents; statistical data on dues, type of talent, affiliation, insurance, expenses, and wages; and memoranda pertaining to AAAA charter, employment agencies for performers, and jurisdictional dispute settlement (1950-1952). Also publications, including issues of Equity (newsletter of AEA, 1929-1952); clippings on various merger proposals (1950-1960); and newsletters and bulletins of member unions (1951).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6046: Archives Union File (AUF)
Entertainers -- United States -- Salaries, pensions, etc; Actors.; Entertainers.; Musicians.; Trade-union merger. United States.; Trade-unions. Actors. United States.; Trade-unions. Broadcasting employees. United States.; Trade-unions. Entertainers. United States.; Trade-unions. Musicians. United States.; Actors' Equity Association; American Federation of Radio Artists; American Guild of Musical Artists; American Guild of Variety Artists; Associated Actors and Artistes of America; Bernard and Reis Company.; Chorus Equity Association; Television Authority; Aronson, Robert Louis; Bernays, Edward L., 1891 -; Jones, Raymond; Reel, Frank; Simon, Louis; Warren, Edgar F.; Webster, Margaret
2294679
- Merger Study Materials: Branch's Reply to Questionnaires AEA, AGVA, CEA, AGMA, AFRA (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Merger Study Materials: Bernard Reis & Co. Merger Proposal (May 20, 1940) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Merger Study Materials: "On Cue" AFRA Bulletin, Chicago (July/August 1952) (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Merger Study Materials: Los Angeles Merger Plan Conference (May 26, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Merger Study Materials: University Merger Proposal (May 26, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Merger Study Materials: Chicago Merger Plan Conference (May 22, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Merger Study Materials: NY Merger Plan Conference (May 19-20, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Merger Study Materials: Original University Merger Proposal with Modifications (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Merger Study Materials: Radio and TV Wages and Salaries, US Department of Labor BLS (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Merger Study Materials: New York Meetings (4/9-10/52) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Merger Study Materials: University Study Group Progress Report (March 25, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Merger Study Materials: Meeting of AFRA National Board (4/14/52) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Merger Study Materials: Draft Proposals Plans A,B,C (March 1952) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Merger Study Materials: Project Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Merger Study Materials: New York Meetings on Merger Project Summary (January 21-23, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Merger Study Materials: Misc. Notes, Professor Aronson (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Merger Study Materials: Interview Questions (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Merger Study Materials: Interview Contacts and Notes (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Merger Study Materials: Interviews (1/25-4/14/52) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Merger Study Materials: Merger Questionnaire Replies (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Merger Study Materials: AGVA News (September 1951) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Merger Study Materials: Proposed Constitution for AFRA/TVA Merger (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Merger Study Materials: Memo on Proposed CAE-AEA Merger (1951) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Edward Bernays' Survey (October 6, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Merger Study Materials: SAG Memo on TVA (August 18, 1949) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Merger Study Materials: Merger Proposals 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Merger Study Materials: AEA Special Council Meeting to Discuss Merger Proposal (November 29, 1948) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Merger Study Materials: AEA Special Council Meeting to Discuss Merger Proposal (November 22, 1948) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Merger Study Materials: Principles of Merger, University Project (March 14, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Member Union Background Material: AGVA, Accountant's Report (12/31/51) (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Coverage of Merger Issue in Equity Magazine and News Media: "Stand By", NY AFRA Bulletin (January 1952) (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Coverage of Merger Issue in Equity Magazine and News Media: Equity Magazine (2/52-4/52) (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Coverage of Merger Issue in Equity Magazine and News Media: Equity Magazine (1/51-12/51), irregular (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Coverage of Merger Issue in Equity Magazine and News Media: Equity Magazine (5/40-12/50) (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Coverage of Merger Issue in Equity Magazine and News Media: Equity Magazine (6/29-10/39), irregular (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Member Union Background Material: TVA, Accountant's Report (10/31/51) (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Member Union Background Material: AEA, Accountant's Report (4/20/51) (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Member Union Background Material: AGMA, Accountant's Report (9/30/51) (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Member Union Background Material: AFRA, Accountant's Report (4/30/51) (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Member Union Background Material: AFRA, Accountant's Report (11/30/51) (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Member Union Background Material: AFRA, Half Dues Members (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Member Union Background Material: CEA, Accountant's Report (9/30/51) (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Merger Study Materials: Joint Study Group Merger Proposal, NYSSILR UCLA (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Member Union Background Material: AGVA, Annual Report (7/31/51) (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Coverage of Merger Issue in Equity Magazine and News Media: Newsclippings (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Member Union Background Material: AGVA, Agency Regulations and Sample Agreements (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Member Union Background Material: Membership Statistics (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Member Union Background Material: Union Agreements and Working Rules (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Member Union Background Material: Union Constitutions (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Bibliographical Data and Notes on Entertainment Unionism (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Associated Actors and Artists of America: Agency Control, Sample Agreements (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Associated Actors and Artists of America: Employment Services (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Associated Actors and Artists of America: Branch Jurisdiction (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Associated Actors and Artists of America: Accountant's Report (4/30/51) (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Associated Actors and Artists of America: Historical Sketch (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Merger Study Materials: Chicago Mass Meeting to Discuss Merger Proposal (8/13/52) (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Merger Study Materials: New York Mass Meeting to Discuss Merger Proposal (8/7/52) (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Member Union Background Material: AGVA, Accountant's Report (7/31/51) (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Miscellaneous Unions (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Tailor and Garment Unions (Box 2, Folder 12)
- General Office Bulletin (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Teacher Unions (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Glass Bottles and Hotel/Restaurant Unions (Box 2, Folder 9)
- International Unions (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Lithographer Unions (Box 2, Folder 7)
- AFL Federal Labor Unions (Box 2, Folder 6)
- State of New Jersey (Box 2, Folder 5)
- United States Circuit Court of Appeals (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Flyers (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The Exponent (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Exponent (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 1)